Guide to the Jack Rottier photographs and papers of the C and O Canal, 1952-1974 MS2037
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Jack Rottier photographs and papers of the C and O Canal
1952-1974
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Rottier, John M. (Jack)
MS2037
1.5 Linear Feet
Jack Rottier (1910-1988) was a photographer for the National Capital Region of the National Park Service from the early 1960s until he retired in 1975. Collection contains photographs and tranparencies. The material dates from 1952-74.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Jack Rottier
Historical or Biographical Note
Jack Rottier (1910-1988) was a photographer for the National Capital Region of the National Park Service from the early 1960s until he retired in 1975. Throughout his life he was an active member of the C & O Canal Association.
Jack Rottier was born in Bellaire, Michigan. He served in the Army in World War II and graduated from the Medill School of Journalism at Northwestern University. He moved to the Washington area about 1950 as a photographer for the American Forest Products Industries. He later joined the commerce Department, which which he photographed trade fairs overseas, and then the Bureau of Land Management in the Interior Department, where he worked until transferring to the Park Service.
In the course of his career with the Park Service, Rottier contributed to the photographic record of Lady Bird Johnson's beautification program and the development of the Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts in Washington and the Wolf Trap Farm Park for the Performing Arts in Vienna.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains black and white photographs, negatives, color transparencies, and several articles and booklets. This material dates from 1952-74. Jack Rottier was an active member of the C & O Canal Association and these are photographs that he took. All of this material relates to the C & O Canal including images of Canal House, boats, wildlife, cyclists, kayakers, Justice William O. Douglas and various aqueducts.
Washington (D.C.); Chesapeake and Ohio Canal (Md. and Washington, D.C.); Photographs; Canals; Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historical Park; Rottier, John M. (Jack); Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association
- Fort Frederick, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General note
  Text with photograph: "28 Oct 96 RHD The hole shown in this picture was filled in 5 - 10 years ago and the canon moved to the visitors center." Text on negative sleeve: "CO-1 Fort Frederick J. Rottier Falls Church, VA."
- Fort Frederick -- View thru gate, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-2 Fort Frederick J. Rottier View thru gate Jack Rottier 1207 S. Dale Dr. Annandale, VA."
- Big Pool at Fort Frederick State Park, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Text on photograph: "CO-3 Big Pool - a natural pool form by the water of the canal. It is at Ft. Frederick State Park, downstream from Hancock, Md." Text with photograph: "Big Pool at Ft Frederick State Park" Text on negative sleeve: "Looking upstream"
- Culvert above Big Pool near Ernstville, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-4 Tunnel above Big Pool." Text with photograph: "Culvert above Big Pool, near Ernstville. Built to provide access to Cherry Run Ferry."
- Great Tonoloway Creek Aqueduct, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-5 Aqueduct J. Rottier" Text with negative: " Great Tonoloway Creek Aqueduct Great Tonoloway Creek"
- George Keefer, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Text on photograph: "CO-6 G o. A. Keefer, North Branch, Md. Born on house at Lock. 61 in 1883. In 1901 started to work for the C & O Canal at the age of 19 - worked for C & O until it discontinued operations in 1924. In 1916 he became lock tender at Lock -75 and still lives in the canal house at this Lock. He was paid 38.50 per month. He had to sign all weight bills. He said the locks were operated day and night and so he had to be available at all hours. He had no bell the 'boat captains would just holler.' he reports. He is now working for the B & O R.R. and rents the Lock House from the Nat. Govt. This house is more than 100 years old. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text with photograph: "George Keefer of North Branch"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-7 Geo. A. Keefer North Branch tender on L-75 (see CO-6) J.Rottier"
  Text with photograph: "George A. Keefer"
- George A. Keefer, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-6 Geo. A. Keefer North Branch, MD. J. Rottier Born on L-61- 1883 1901 worked for C & O - started when 19 - worked to 1924 - tended locks - moved to house on L-75 in 1916 - still lives there - was paid 38.50 a month Had to sign all weight bills in 1918 - biggest year - 700 boats - locks operated day & night - had no bell - boatmen would just holler - raised his own vegetables. Now working gor B & O, R.R. Retiring in Sept. L-75 rebuilt in 1921 of N.C. Pine."
  Text with negative: "George Keefer"
- James Eaton and Sam Hower, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Text on print: "CO-8 James Eaton, Cumberland (left) and Sam Hower, Nt. Cap. Parks policeman taking about the old canal days. Eaton was born on a canal boat. HIs Father Charles and grandfather Randolph, worked on the Eaton. James worked on the canal unti it discontinued operations in 1924. The men are standing on an old gangplank, taken from a canal boat."
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-8 James Eaton Cumberland Sam Hower Cap. Parks Police standing on old gang plank James Eaton - Charles " - father Randolph " - grandfather James was born on canal boat worked on boat until 1924"
  Text with photograph: "James Eaton & Sam Hower"
- James Eaton, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Text on photograph: "C)-9. James Eaton showing two sets of bells which were attached to the hames on the horse's or mule's collar. These were owned by Eaton's grandfather and more than 100 years old.
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-9 James Eaton with bells - Cumberland, Md. These bells owned by Randolph Eaton, his grandfather wound on hames of mule harness. J. Rottier"
- Terminus of Canal, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-10 Terminus of Canal Cumberland, MD."
- Terminus of Canal, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-11 - Terminus of Canal Cumberland, MD."
- C & O Terminal, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Text on photograph: "CO-12. Terminus of the C&O canal at Cumberland. Train is of the Western Maryland line. Photo by Jack Rottier"
- Terminus of Canal Lock-76, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Text on negative sleeve: "C-12 Terminus of Canal Lock-76 Cumberland, MD."
  Text with negative: "CO-12 C&O Terminus at Cumberland"
- Terminus of Canal Lock 76, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-13 Terminus of Canal Lock 76 Cumberland"
- Terminus of Canal Lock 76, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-14 Terminus of Canal Lock 76 Cumberland, MD."
- Lock 76, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Text on photograph: "CO-15. Lock 76. Last lock on the canal at Cumberland. Old Lock house in foreground. Photo by Jack Rottier"
- Terminus of Canal Lock 76, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-15 Terminus of Canal Lock 76 Cumberland, MD. House - Tender's home over 100 years old.
- Terminus Lock 76, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-16 Terminus - Lock - 76 Remains of old boat in foreground - House over 100 yrs old, occupied by Randolph Easton, when lock tender - now occupied by James Eaton"
- Canal House at Lock #75, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Text on photograph: "CO-17. Canal House at Lock #75. George Keefer, former employee of the C&O is living in home. North Branch, Md. Photo by J. Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-17 Lock - 75 Keefer's Home North Branch, MD House over 100 years old - made of pine"
- House at Lock - 75, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Text on photograph: "CO-18. Canal House at Lock 75. George Keefer, former employee of the C&O is now living in home. North Branch, MD. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-18 House at Lock-75 Keefer's Home House over 100 yrs old made of Pine logs"
- Lock 75 Keefer's Home, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-19 Lock 75 Keefer's Home North Branch"
  Text with negative: "Srr CO 7"
- Lock 75, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Text on photograph: "CO-20,. Lock 75 at North Branch, Md. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-20 Lock-75 North Branch, MD"
- Old Canal Boat, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-21 Hull (front) of old canal boat Spring Gap"
- Hull of old canal boat, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Text on photograph: "CO-22 Hull of old canal boat along the canal at Spring Gap, MD. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-22 Hull of old canal boat Sping Gap"
- Hull of old canal boat, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Text on photograph: "CO-23. Hull of old canal boat along the canal at Spring Gap, Md. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-23 Hull of old cnal boat Spring Gap."
- Pig sty on canal, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Text on negative: "CO-24 Pig sty on canal Spring Gap."
- Geese along canal, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Text on photograph: "CO-25. Domestic Geese from nearby farm enjoy the water in the canal. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-25 Geese along canal"
- Confluence - Ginneman Run, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-26 Confluence - Ginneman Run and canal"
- Canal from bridge, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Text on photograph: "CO-27. Canal from bridge at Old Town, Md. Here the Old Town Sportsmen Club has repaired the gates at the canal and stocked with fish for children to fish. Lock 71.
  Text on sleeve: "CO-27 Canal from bridge Ginneman Run-"
- Old Town Sportsmen Club, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Text on photograph: "Photo by Jack Rottier Old Town Sportsmen Club has rented this canal house from the Govt. for the use of their club. It is at Lock 71 and the club has stocked the canal at this section wit fish for youngsters. Photo by Jack Rottier CO-28"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-28 Old Town Sportsmen Club old canal house at Old Town Lock-71"
- Lock-71 Old Town, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-29 Lock - 71 - Old Town owned by club. Bad neg"
- Lock - 71 Old Town, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-30 Lock-71 Old Town fixed by Sportsmen Club."
- Lock - 71 Old Town, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-31 Lock - 71 Old Town"
- Old Town - rifle range, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-32 Old Town - Rifle Range for Sportsman Club."
- Hut at Old Town, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-33 Hut at Old Town"
- Lock 71 at Old Town, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Text on photograph: "CO-34. Lock 71 at Old Town where the Old Town Sportsman Club has fixed up the gates to hold back the water and have stocked the canal for youngsters to fish. Photo by Jack Rottier"
- View of Lock 70, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Text on photograph: "CO-35. View of Lock 70 at Old Town. Children may fish in this section of the canal which is stocked each year by the Old Town Sportsman Club. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-35 View of Lock 70 Old Town Area of canal stocked with fish by Sportsmen club"
  Text with photograph and negative sleeve: "Shows site o Chesap's original dwelling"
- View of canal from highway below, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-36 View of canal from highway below Old Town bad neg)
- Paw Paw Tunnel, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-37 Paw Paw Tunnel W- Entrance Sam Hower Nat. Cap. Parks Police Tunnel - 3000 ft long 24 ft. wide - built thru solid rock - regular Red Brick (house) - 7 layers well followed"
- Paw Paw Tunnel, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-38 Paw Paw Tunnel W- Entrance Sam Hower"
- Paw Paw Tunnel, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-39 Paw Paw Tunnel Inside looking out of E-Entrance"
- Paw Paw Tunnel, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Text on negative: "CO-40 Paw Paw Tunnel looking out E- Entrance Sam Hower"
- Paw Paw Tunnel, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Text on photograph: "CO-41 Inside of tunnel at south [south crossed off and handwritten north over it] end. Tunnel is 3,000 ft. long, cut thru solid rock, - arched with seven layers of ordinary red house brick. Tunnel is still in fine repair and can be used for the roadway. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "Paw Paw Tunnel looking out E- entrance Sam Hower"
- Paw Paw Tunnel, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Text on photograph: "CO-42 South entrance of Paw Paw tunnel. Photo by Jack Rottier This is down stream portal - which is north end"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-42 Paw Paw Tunnel E-Entrance waterfalls"
  Text with photograph and negative sleeve: "CO-42 North End Paw Paw Tunnel"
- Signs of beavers at work, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Text on photograph: "CO-43. Signs of Beaver at work at Paw Paw tunnel. Sam Hower, Nat. Cap. Parks policeman. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-43 Signs of beaver at work W-Entrance Paw Paw Tunnel"
- Potomac from R.R. Bridge, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-44 Potomac - from R.R. Bridge Green Ridge Station J. Rottier 108 S. Greenwood, Dr. Falls Church, VA."
- Canal tow path, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Text on photograph: "CO-45 Canal tow path near Green Ridge Station, Md. Typical tow path on which the parkway will be built, wherever feasible Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-45 Canal tow path near Green Ridge Station Looking east."
- Tow Path near Green Ridge Station, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-46 Tow path near Green Ridge Station looking west."
- Canal near Green Ridge Station, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  Text on negative sleeve: "Canal near Green Rdige Station looking downstream"
- Blossoms along canal, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Text on photograph: "CO-48. Blossoms of shadbush along canal. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: " CO-48 Blossoms along canal"
- 15 Mile Greek, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-49 15-Mile Greek near Little Orleans"
  Text with negative: "CO-49 15-Mile Creek near Little Orleans"
- Flood control bridge, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-50 Flood Control Bridge 15-mile Creek Little Orleans
- Fishing on Potomac, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-51 Fishing-on Potomac near Little Orleans"
- Fishing - Potomac, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-52 Fishing-Potomac near Little Orleans Mr. & Mrs. Geo. Humbertson Somerset, PA."
- Aqueduct Little Orleans, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-53 Aqueduct Little Orleans"
- Aqueduct Little Orleans, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Text on sleeve negative: "CO-45 Aqueducts Little Orleans"
- Wild Flowers, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  Text on photograph: "CO-55. Wild Flowers along canal Phot by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-55 Wild Flowers along canal"
- Aqueduct Little Orleans, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  Text on photograph: "CO-56 Aqueduct over 15-mile creek at Little Orleans, Md. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-56 Aqueduct Little Orleans"
- Farm, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-57 Farm Little Orleans"
- Potomac River, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  Text on photograph: "CO*59. View of Potomac river, C&O cnanal[sic] and Western Maryland R.R. taken below Little Orleans. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-59 River view below Little Orleans"
- River view along canal, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  Text on negative sleeve: "OC-60 River view along canal"
- Lake along canal, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  Text on photograph: "CO-61. Lake along canal at the Woodmont Rod & Gun club. Located below Little Orleans. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-61 Lake along canal Woodmont Rod & Gun Club"
- Lock below Little Orleans, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  Text on photograph: "CO-62. Lock in bad repair below Little Orleans along the canal. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-62 Lock Woodmont Rod & Gun Club."
- View of country side, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  Text on photograph: "CO*63. View of country side taken from highway near Hancock. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-63 View of road near Hancock"
  Text with photograph: "Western Maryland countryside - Brooks Farm on roundetop road near Hancock"
- View of Hancock from bridge, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  Text on photograph: "CO-64. View of canal approaching Hancock, taken from bridge. This will be ther terminus of the parkway. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-64 View of Hancock from bridge"
- Fishing in Little Pool, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  Text on photograph: "CO-65. Fishing in Little Pool, a section of the canal below Hancock. Emil E. Krampf, cumberland, Md. fishing while Sam Hower of Nat. Cap. Parks Police Dept. looks on. Photo by Jack Rottier"
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-65 Fishing Lillt Pool near Hancock Emil E. Krampf 403 - Arch. St. Cumberland Sam Hower (on left)"
- Fishing Little Pool, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  Text on negative sleeve: "CO-66 Fishing Little Pool Sam Hower Jack Rottier 108 S. Greenwood, Dr. Falls Church, VA."
- View across river of Cherry Run, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  Text with negative: "CO-67 - View across river of Cherry Run, Morgan County WV from near Ernstville MD, ca. 1952, 4 x 5 negative"
- Wildflower and rowboat on water, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  Text with transperencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) wildflower 2) rowboat on water ca. 1952"
- Hillside trail and towpath, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  Text with transperencies: "2 2 x 2 color transperancies 1) hillside trail 2) towpath ca. 1952"
- Canal with rowboat and river scene, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  Text with transperancies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) canal rowboat 2) river scene ca. 1952"
- Train crossing Lock 76, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) train crossing Lock 76 at Cumberland 2) Lock 76 at Cumberland ca. 1952"
- Towpath and river scene, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  Text with transperancies: "2 2 x 2 color transperancies 1)towpath 2) river scene ca. 1952"
- Dogwood trees and small cabin, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) dogwood trees in bloom 2) small cabin ca. 1952"
- Lock 76 at Cumberland, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  Text with transparency: "2 x 2 transparency, Lock 76 at Cumberland ca. 1952"
- Fisherman on riverbank, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  Text with transparency: "2 x 2 transparency fisherman on riverbank ca. 1952"
- Riverbend, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  Text with transparency: "2 x 2 transparency - riverbend, ca. 1952"
- Single-arch aqueduct, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  Text with transparency: "2 x 2 color transparency, single-arch aqueduct ca. 1952"
- Farmhouse and outbuildings, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  Text with transparency: "2 x 2 color transparency - farmhouse and outbuildings
- wildflowers and aqueduct, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) wildflowers 2) single-arch aqueduct with railings ca. 1952"
- Single-arch aqueduct, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  Text with transparency: "2 x 2 color transparency single-arch aqueduct ca. 1952"
- Dip net rig, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  Text with transperancy: "2 2 x 2 color transperancies dip net rig & two people, Potomac river ca. 1952"
- Hilly landscape and wildflowers, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  Text with transperancy: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) hilly landscape 2) wildflowers ca. 1952"
- Aqueduct and dip net rig, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transperancies 1) Little Tonoloway Creek aqueduct 2) dip net rig & 2 people, Potomac River ca. 1952
- Streams, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies stream(s) ca. 1952"
- River and town (Hancock), Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) river 2) town (Hancock) ca. 1952"
- Old house at Lock 76 and Potomac River, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  Text with transparency: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) old house at Lock 76, Cumberland 2) Potomac River in Cumberland ca. 1952"
- Paw Paw Tunnel, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) looking down the canal from portal of Paw Paw Tunnel 2) Paw Paw Tunnel ca. 1952"
- Upstream portal of Paw Paw Tunnel, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) upstream portal the Paw Paw Tunnel 2) upstream portal of Paw Paw Tunnel"
- Paw Paw Tunnel and rowboat, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  Text with transperancies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) downstream portal of Paw Paw Tunnel 2) Boat ruin ca. 1952"
- Ridgley, WV, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color tranparencies 1) Ridgley, WV ca. 1952"
- Dogwood tree and railroad, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  Text with photograph: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) dogwood tree in bloom 2) railroad bridge across river ca. 1952"
- Lock gate, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  Text with tranparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies Lock gate ca. 1952"
- Paw Paw Tunnel, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) looking out of upstream portal of Paw Paw Tunnel 2) looking out of upstream portal of Paw Paw Tunnel ca. 1952"
- Dogwood tree and C&O towpath, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  Text with transparency: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) dogwood tree in bloom 2) C&O towpath, probably at Big Pool, probably of Spillway Piers ca. 1952"
- Canal lock, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 transparencies canal lock ca. 1952"
- Train, canal lock and river scene, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) train and canal lock 2) river scene ca. 1952"
- Lock and backyard scene, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies 1) probably Lock 71 2) trashy backyard scene ca. 1952"
- Woman, child and Reefer house, Circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  Text with transparencies: "2 2 x 2 color transparencies - 1) woman & child 2) Reefer House, Lock 71 ca. 1952"
- C&O canal at Fletchers boathouse, 1968 April (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Text with photograph: "4 x 4 colo photo, C&O canal at Fletchers boathouse, April 1968"
- C&O Canal at Fletcher's Boathouse, 1968 April (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Text with negative: "2 1/4 x 2 1/4 color negative C&O canal at Fletcher's boathouse, April 1968"
- Cyclists on C&O canal, 1968 April (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Text with photograph: "4 x 4 color photo - cyclists on C&O canal near Fletcher's boathouse, April 1968."
  Text with negative: "2 x 2 color negative cyclists on C&O cnal near Fletcher's boathouse, April 1968"
- Cyclists near C&O canal, 1968 April (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Text with photograph: "4 x 4 color photo of cyclists on C&O canal near Fletcher's boathouse, April 1968"
  Text with negative: "2 1/4 x 2 1/4 color negative of cyclists on C&O canal near Fletcher's boathouse April 1968"